hello everyone I hope this season is
treating you well we're in a great time
of transition here when early spring and
late winter intermingle mud and Ice
Frost and
flowers it's a sort of time that often
makes me feel a bit impatient for things
to move along but I try to remind myself
that it is this very waiting period that
is so crucial in our lives that patience
is needed for things to work themselves
out it may feel like nothing is
happening and then right under your nose
the flowers are suddenly blooming and
the Sun is warm and the days are long
again much in the same way I know the
future will reveal itself in time and
and I can accept it despite reservations
and seek out the beauty and whatever it
entails taking
hard for a springtime treat I decided to
make some time for fun activities and
went to visit my friend and she showed
me her new chicken coue she had built
herself she sent me home with a
beautiful collection of Guinea and
chicken eggs of all colors and sizes
which I had to put to good use of
[Music]
course as you know from my previous
video I've been working through some big
emotions as well as practical
considerations for the months to come
taking time off work to be a new mother
and figuring out what the years ahead
hold in store for us I couldn't help but
look to nature for insight seeing the
way that all these plants dormant
throughout the winter pop through the
snow only to be eaten up by hungry
Critters fresh out of
hibernation as humans we may take
setbacks like this to heart and become
overly cautious afraid of everything
that might go wrong if we allow
ourselves to step into the unknown I
think our complex Minds can work against
us sometimes and yet those plants that
are nibbled away aren't bothered in the
least they just keep growing putting
what energy they have into life because
for them there is no point to existing
if you can't grow it's an absolute
[Music]
must
I am waiting for the muffins to finish
baking and it was just so much fun to
look at all the different eggs and all
the different colors my mother had
chickens for several years and it
brought back so many memories of those
Easter eggs as I'm waiting for the
muffins to finish baking because I'm
very hungry I am going to go around my
home and just look see what stands out
to me see what I want to focus on next
week for simplifying everything I'm
going to make a very involved video of
going through everything and I hope it
will encourage all of you maybe if
you're doing a little bit of spring
cleaning or reorganizing or even
decluttering you can do so along with me
I will be slowly piecing the process and
putting it all together so I hope you
enjoy it and we will see how it goes I'm
sure I will have some sentimental items
from my childhood that may be hard to
part with one one of my goals with
simplifying my home getting rid of
unnecessary items being more more
mindful with my spending overall is to
make room and make space in my mind for
projects that I really want to get done
and one of them is making this door
more attractive I have seen so many
beautiful doors on homes but they're
very expensive so instead of getting
a actual wood very nice door we're going
to redo this one I think what will
elevate it is to do a much darker color
I have a lot of paint swatches and I
think one of the colors I'm considering
is more of a terracotta color like a
rusty orange red and I think it would
look quite lovely I hope it will be able
to elevate a very inexpensive door and
make it look a lot nicer so there you go
there's just some ideas with reasons why
I like to simplify my home cuz I feel
like I'm more mental space to work on
these little projects that I've really
been meaning to and coming from someone
who has spent a long time sanding
repurposing and upcycling things from
thrift stores and flea markets with a
lot of patience a lot of time a lot of
simplifying there can be a lot of fun
little projects you can get around to
doing so that is my goal now the theme
of this year as I put in my last video
is simplification budgeting I was raised
by very frugally minded parents and so
um I want to continue that and instill
that in our own children as well that is
certainly the whole theme of this year
so perhaps I will inspire you as well if
you've been wanting to get certain
things in your own life in order and if
not maybe you can just enjoy this little
peruse around the home trying to figure
out what projects I need to get done the
muffins are almost done baking and the
smell is Dr driving me crazy so
hopefully I'll get to enjoy them very
soon my family has taught me that the
most important thing to do when faced
with an uncertain future is to live as
simply as possible and be humble in
one's desires and consume with
intention I was raised this way by
parents that always showed me the
importance of having just enough giving
generously and enjoying the little
things living simply doesn't ask me to
live a Spartan life devoid of all my
artistic desires and small Joys I am an
artist after all and will forever be
redecorating my home in increasingly
ridiculous Whimsical ways utilizing the
treasures of thrift stores and estate
sales I will enjoy my candles and books
but these things will be carefully
considered when they enter my home I
found it to be incredibly fruitful to
examine not only what I consume but why
I consume it and make sure I'm making
choices with intention creativity and
[Music]
practicality
while perusing my home I couldn't help
but take a peek at my husband's Crystal
collection he likes to go on Long hikes
in the mountains keeping an eye out for
crystals sticking out of the ground he's
found quite a few over the years and
something that always strikes me about
them is how imperfect they look in their
natural form before being polished and
perfected by chemicals and
machines it always makes me wonder how
much I've allowed myself to be formed by
the world around me making sure I don't
lose sight of my natural
[Music]
self speaking of natural self I decided
it was high time to give away some
clothes that no longer fit me before
pregnancy I really started prioritizing
my health a couple years ago and happily
no longer fit in some old items these
belong to a body that's stressed way too
much without eating nutritious meals a
sign of success to be
[Music]
sure going forward I want to be a lot
more mindful with what I consume and why
I consume it I made a video a while back
in Autumn of my kind of low by Autumn
and and getting on a budget and it was
really insightful and really fruitful I
was also raised by parents that
instilled a lot of these more mindful
Frugal values within us as I said in my
last video this is a new era and I am
changing so quickly I I'm just shocked
and I hope to encourage you if you are
coming into the springtime or just a new
season that maybe this is a great time
to do some simplifying decluttering
creating goals as well as being gentle
to yourself and mindful in the present
it's all an interesting Balancing Act
but I do notice that when great internal
change happens within pretty much
everything without needs to change as
well and I kind of like that it's a true
transformation I have restocked my Etsy
shop I do not have too many items on
there but I just I do have some and and
so I really appreciate it I am working
on some new art pieces I hope to have
those at some point in the future
everything moves slowly in my life right
now slower than ever before I also am
doing recordings and live streams and
fun videos on patreon as well and that
has been really fun it's been super fun
to connect with a small community there
I appreciate all your kindness and
support I hope you're all doing well let
me know if you're doing some spring
cleaning down below and I'm sending you
so much love
[Music]
goodbye